a good pair of dumbbells can be the
catalyst for your home gym thanks to
their versatility the rep fitness hex
dumbbells are a great option for any
level weight lifter offering dumbbells
as light as two and a half pounds and as
heavy as 125 pounds the fully knurled
handle offers optimal grip and the low
odor rubber allows you to skip the
airing out process completely and get
right to it
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym and in full
review today i've got the rep fitness
hex dumbbells in this video i'm going to
walk you through everything these
dumbbells have to offer the features the
price some pros and cons and as always
who should and who should not add these
to their home gym but before we get
started i gotta let you know we have
reviewed a ton of dumbbells on
barbin.com to find out more about our
best picks just google barbin best
dumbbells and that list will pull right
up for you and you can find out which
one we like the best
[Music]
okay so let's dig into what i like about
these dumbbells let's start with the
fully knurled handles it's going to
allow you to get that maximum grip for
your lifts without fear of them slipping
out of your hands since they are coated
in rubber you do have a better chance of
preserving your home floor thanks to
this hexagonal shape here you'll find
that if you drop them they're not going
to roll away from you and plus you can
use them for different push-up
variations as well
another really cool thing is that not
only can you get them as a pair but you
can also get them as a set like we have
here
all right now with all those great
things being said there are a few
potential cons with these dumbbells
first and foremost as always the price
these are an expensive set of dumbbells
here there are cheaper options available
to you online but with any expensive
product you're buying the quality which
is really evident once you get your
hands on these bad boys right here and
number two available space if you're
already tied on space you might want to
consider just going down the adjustable
dumbbell route
if you purchase a full set like this
right here it might dominate too much
space which might not be good for you
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some money
since these dumbbells are available in
both individual pairs and as a full set
you're looking at various pricing
options let's talk about the full sets
the 5 to 50 pound set you see here today
that's going to cost you 1100
if you wanted to go from 5 to 75 pounds
that's going to cost you 200
and the 5 to 100 pounds set that's going
to cost you 3 600
if you wanted to skip that lighter
weight you can start at 55 pounds 55 to
75 pounds that's gonna cost you 12.50
and if you wanted to go 80 to 100 pounds
that's gonna cost you 1500 bucks the
individual pairs they start as low as 15
for the two and a half pound dumbbells
and finish as high as 520
for the 125 pound dumbbells also worth
mentioning this rack you see here today
is not included whatsoever that's going
to cost you an extra 180 bucks which is
something to really consider when you're
making that purchase
okay so when we talk about the build of
the rep fitness hex dumbbells there's a
few things worth mentioning you'll
notice that anything under 20 pounds is
gonna have a handle diameter of 28
millimeters 20 pounds and above be 34
millimeters the handles are fully
knurled giving you that maximum grip for
your lifts and they're also chrome
plated which gives them a nice shine
the heads of the dumbbells are hexagonal
shape meaning they're not gonna roll
away from you and you can do those
push-up variations that i mentioned
earlier and they're also attached via
friction welding which is really gonna
extend their life and adding to that
durability
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the features
now of these dumbbells it's worth
mentioning they're not ergonomically
shaped which might get on your nerves
but in my time with them i enjoyed it i
found it perfectly fine that they
weren't shaped that way
since they are available in individual
pairs or full set
if you don't want to put all that money
down up front with the full set you can
buy a couple pairs and you can expand
them over time as you do become stronger
the low odor rubber is really going to
allow you to just open them out of the
box
get straight to it don't have to let
them air out all right so i'm going to
walk you guys through these dumbbells
now as i previously mentioned anything
under 20 pounds you're going to notice
this handle has a diameter of 28
millimeters while 20 pounds and above
has a 34 millimeter diameter and since
the handles are fully knurled you're
going to get a good grip no matter where
you position your hands now since they
are coated in rubber they're going to be
great for your home floors but it's also
gonna protect the dumbbells themselves
the hexagonal shape is great in my
opinion also because they're not gonna
roll away from you plus you can do
different variations of push-ups if you
want to incorporate that into your
workouts while the numbers listed here
don't really pop out at you
you can still easily see which one is
which so there's no confusion when you
go to grab a pair of dumbbells
[Music]
okay so let's talk about who should
purchase the rep fitness hex dumbbells
well
if you're looking for a high quality
product that does feature a rubber
coating you're going to love these
they're not going to ruin your floors
and since they are in a hexagonal shape
they're not going to roll away from your
feet plus you can use them for push-ups
if you want to and since you can buy
them in individual pairs that gives you
the option to expand over time as you do
become stronger okay so who should not
buy these dumbbells well it really comes
down to three different things
these are pretty expensive and the rack
featured here does not come with your
purchase
so there are cheaper options out there
but those options may not be of high of
quality as these dumbbells are i
personally like the shape but if you are
looking for an ergonomically shaped
handle you might want to consider that
as well
and finally it really boils down to
space
if you don't have enough space for full
rack or say you have individual pairs
you don't have space for them to be
lying around you might want to consider
going down the route of an adjustable
pair of dumbbells because those take up
a fraction of the footprint
[Music]
well that's all i have for you all today
on the rep fitness hex dumbbells i think
this is a high quality product thanks
for the rubber coating they're ideal for
at-home usage meaning they're not going
to ruin your floors the hexagonal shape
is great they're not going to roll away
from your feet plus you can use them for
different variations of push-ups if you
want to and this fully knurled handle
well that's going to give you that
maximum grip for your lifts thanks for
watching everybody i hope this video was
helpful in your pursuit for your next
set of dumbbells as always head over to
barbin.com and you can read up more
about this product just search barbin
rep fitness hex dumbbells that article
will pull up and you can go over
everything we talked about here today
see you next time
[Music]
you